Jeff Haynes

DATA MANAGER / FRONT END DEVELOPER

Profile

I am a data manager & developer with more than eight years of experience. I currently work as a technical data manager for large contract research organisation, so I have plenty of experience working well with others as part of a team or agency. I am an enthusiastic and dedicated professional with extensive experience across all areas of database

management, design and development. A proactive individual with a logical approach to challenges, I perform effectively even within a highly pressurised working environment. I am quick to grasp new ideas and concepts, and to develop innovative and creative solutions to problems

Experience

Technical Data Manager

2013 - Present

INC Research » Lewes, UK

External Data Manager working with a major global pharmaceutical company and its vendors. I am responsible for the programming, specification building and delivering external data for large EU-wide clinical trials.

Health Informatics Developer

2012 - 2013

Sciensus » Brighton, UK

Information design, visual design and implementation of web reporting solutions for a wide range of commercial and health authority clients. Regular duties included: visual design and HTML, CSS & JavaScript, SQL and C# (MVC)

Safety System Expert

2006 - 2012

Novartis Pharmaceuticals » Horsham, UK

Responsible for the maintenance of the safety database configuration and change control processes and for the technical support to the business users of safety data tools. Providing analysis and queries using SQL and SAS for management decisions leading to Quality Assurance reporting and Corrective Action Planning

Clinical Data Manager

2004 - 2006

Covance Cardiac Safety Services » Crawley, UK

Accountable for study data accuracy and timeliness and responsible for the global contact and escalation point between Covance Cardiac Safety Services (CCSS) and their sponsors for all data related activities, Managing a team of Data Management & Statistics staff within their Clinical Trial Operation team, Maintenance and creation of SAS programs, Visual Basic Scripts, Transact SQL scripts, system testing processes, and all associated documentation.

Systems Developer

1999 - 2004

CP Ships (UK) Ltd » Crawley, UK

Developed the Companies new Data Warehouse / OLAP / MIS application holding information relating to revenue, clients and transportation of containers worldwide. Provided Microsoft OLAP services for SQL Server 7.0 to produce extended data sets for European offices. This information presented to user using web based Pivot Table lists and Excel 2000. Additional

reporting provided using OLAP MDX SQL, local cubes and Access 2000. Responsible for the maintenance of an EDI system using Mercator and Trading Partner products plus its VB and SQL server applications to process vessel statistics at each port call and supplying senior management with performance and volume information for globally placed container vessels.

Clinical/Emergency Care Effectiveness Coordinator

1992 - 1999

Brighton Health Care » Brighton, UK

Various Commercial and System Auditor Roles

1980 - 1992

BT Plc » Brighton | City of London, UK

Various Commercial and System Auditor Roles

Skills

Software

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint, Access, OneNote, Visio, Project), Linux (Ubuntu 12.04), SAS (Enterprise 9.3), SPSS Visio, Visual Source Safe, Visual Studio Team Share, MVC3+,Razor 2+, Entity Framework 4.1, MS SQL Server 2008, LINQ to Entities, DevExpress, SQL Server

Mark-Up & Programming

HTML 4, 5; XHTML 1.1; XML; CSS 2, 3; JavaScript; jQuery; SQL (MySQL, SQL Server).

Platforms

Microsoft Windows; Ubuntu Linux; Apache HTTP Server; Microsoft IIS Server

Pharmaceutical

Pharmacovigilance, Electronic Data Capture, Data Management, GCP, 21 CFR Part 11, CDISC

Education

MSc Evaluation of Clinical Practice

2001

<u>University of Westminster</u> » London, UK

Studies included: Evidence-Based Medicine, Research methods and applied statistics, Change Management, Epidemiology and information

HNC Computer Science

1992

University of Brighton » Brighton, UK

Studies included: Relational Database Management, Structured Programming Languages

Interests

Cycling, technology, photography.

References

